Finding Aid for Office of Financial Aid (University of Michigan) Publications, ca. 1957-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Office of Financial Aid (University of Michigan) publications circa 1957-2001, 1980-1996
University of Michigan. Office of Financial Aid.
0.75 linear feet
05105 Bimu 2
Publications contain applications, brochures, flyers, pamphlets, newsletters, reports, and miscellaneous published items from the University of Michigan’s Office of Financial Aid detailing the administration and disbursement of financial aid to students.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (donor no. 8672 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
See the finding aid for the University of Michigan Office of Financial Aid records group for the office’s history.
The Office of Financial Aid (OFA) Publications record group is divided into seven series: Application Forms and Instructions, 1973-1999; Brochures and Pamphlets, ca 1957-1999; Directions in Financial Aid, 1979/80-1984/85, 1990/91; Flyers and Information Sheets, 1986-1996 and undated; Miscellaneous, 1990-1997; Newsletters, 1971-2001; and Reports, 1977-1989. The researcher should note that there are complete print runs for none of the publications in the record group; holdings for each title consist of more or less scattered sets of issues within the date ranges given.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Funds and scholarships.; Student aid.
Genre Terms:
Newsletters.; Brochures.
- Application Forms and Instructions 1973-1999
  Application Forms and Instructions, 1973-1999 includes blank University of Michigan financial aid applications, worksheets, and FAFSAs (Free Application for Federal Student Aid forms), as well as instructions on how to fill out these forms.
  - 1973-1999 (Box 1)
- Brochures and Pamphlets, ca 1957-1999
  Brochures and Pamphlets, ca 1957-1999 begins with a file containing OFA descriptions of their brochures and pamphlets circa 1994, but many titles are fairly self-explanatory. Required Reading contains information on procedures and next steps for students who have received a financial aid award package from the university.
  The brochures and pamphlets in the "Information for Prospective Students" series underwent several title changes over the years. Holdings include:
  Consider Michigan: Costs and Financial Aid: Information for Prospective Students (ca 1985 and 1988/89-1990/91)
  Michigan can Help: A Guide to Financial Aid for Prospective Students and their Families (1991/92-1992/93)
  Michigan Cares: A Guide to Financial Aid for Prospective Students and their Families (1993/94)
  A Guide to Financial Aid for Prospective Students and their Families (1994/95)
  University of Michigan Financial Aid: A Guide for Prospective Students and their Families (1995/96, September 1997, and September 1998); and Information for Prospective Students and their Families (ca 1996/97-1997/98).
  Similarly, the brochures and pamphlets in the "Information for Prospective Students from Underrepresented Groups" series also have several titles. Also, earlier titles were split into separate brochures for Michigan residents and out-of-state students. Holdings include:
  Consider Michigan: Non-Resident Costs and Financial Aid: Information for Prospective Students from Under-Represented Groups (ca 1985 and 1987/88-1988/89)
  Consider Michigan: Michigan Resident Costs and Financial Aid: Information for Prospective Students from Under-Represented Groups (ca 1985 and 1987/88-1988/89)
  Consider Michigan: Costs and Financial Aid: Information for Prospective Students from Under-Represented Groups (1989/90-1990/91)
  Michigan can Help: A Guide to Financial Aid for Prospective Students from Under-represented Groups and their Families (1991/92)
  Michigan can Help: A Guide to Financial Aid for Underrepresented Minority Groups (1992/93)
  Michigan Cares: A Guide to Financial Aid for Underrepresented Minority Groups (1993/94)
  A Guide to Financial Aid for Underrepresented Minority Groups (1994/95); and
  University of Michigan Financial Aid: A Guide for Underrepresented Minority Students (1995/96).
  - Explanations and Descriptions of OFA Pamphlets 1993, undated (Box 1)
  - Financial Aid, 1970/71-1980/81 (Box 1)
    (supersedes Scholarships, Loans, and Jobs)
  - Financial Aid for Dental Students, 1979/80-1988/89 (Box 1)
  - Information for Prospective Students series, ca 1985-1998 (Box 1)
  - Information for Prospective Students from Underrepresented Groups series, ca 1985-1996 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, ca 1957-1999 (bulk dates 1985-1996) (Box 1)
  - Required Reading, 1983/84, 1986/87, 1990/91-1998/99 (Box 1)
  - Scholarships, Loans, and Jobs, 1962/63-1969/70 (Box 1)
    (precedes Financial Aid)
- Directions in Financial Aid, 1979/80-1984/85, 1990/91
  Directions in Financial Aid, 1979/80-1984/85, 1990/91 is comprised of Directions in Financial Aid, the publication containing the OFA's most official and complete descriptions of the options, programs, and services available to students seeking help financing their University of Michigan educations.
  - 1979/80-1984/85 1990/91 (Box 1)
- Flyers and Information Sheets 1986-1996, undated
  Flyers and Information Sheets, 1986-1996 and undated contains information on the work-study program (including tips on finding and interviewing for work-study jobs), estimated student budgets and expenses for various academic years, overviews of the various types of loans available from government and private organizations, and other handouts for students. The material covers some of the same information content as items in the Brochures and Pamphlets series, albeit in different format.
  - 1986-1996 undated (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous 1990-1997
  The items in the Miscellaneous, 1990-1997 series consist mostly of packets of handouts distributed by the OFA to various university groups, including departmental liaisons and prospective students. Also contained in this series is the Student Employment Handbook for University Employers from 1991.
  - Financial Aid Presentation Handout Packets 1991-1996 (Box 1)
  - OFA Communications Packet 1990 (Box 1)
  - Student Employment Handbook for University Employers, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Work-Study Job Fair Handouts 1996-1997, undated (Box 1)
- Newsletters 1971-2001
  There are three categories of newsletters in the Newsletters, 1971-2001 series: staff newsletters, general student newsletters, and student employment newsletters. The first category includes both in-house newsletters for OFA staff (OFA Bulletin and OFA Busybody) and a more official newsletter designed to be distributed university-wide (Financial Aid Newsletter, or FAN). The general student newsletters (The University of Michigan Office of Financial Aid Newsletter and its successor, Office of Financial Aid Newsletter, contain all of the official information on financial aid options and deadlines, as well as OFA procedures, for students. Finally, the student employment newsletters (Occasional News, Sporadic News, Student Employment Newsletter, Work-Study Monthly, and Work Study Newsletter) all relate to work-study jobs or other aspects of student employment as it relates to financial aid.
  - Staff Newsletters
    - Financial Aid Newsletter (FAN), 1982-1995 (Box 1)
    - OFA Bulletin, 1980-1997, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - OFA Busybody, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
  - Student Newsletters
    - The University of Michigan Office of Financial Aid Newsletter, 1978-1992 (Box 1)
      (precedes Office of Financial Aid Newsletter)
    - Office of Financial Aid Newsletter, 1992-2001 (Box 1)
      (supersedes The University of Michigan Office of Financial Aid Newsletter)
  - Student Employment Newsletters
    - Miscellaneous 1971 (Box 1)
    - Student Employment Newsletter, 1996-1999 (Box 1)
    - Work Study Newsletter, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
- Reports 1977-1989
  The Reports, 1977-1989 series is comprised mainly of OFA reports to the Regents and other university officials regarding the characteristics of students receiving financial aid upon entering the university and their debt loads after graduation. There is also a report describing the computerized information system the office used in 1989.
  - Highlights of the College Work-Study Program at the University of Michigan: Report to the Regents, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Selected Characteristics of Students Receiving Financial Support from the Flint Campus of the University of Michigan, 1974-1976, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Selected Characteristics of Students Receiving Financial Support from the University of Michigan Ann Arbor Campus, 1975-1976 Report to the Regents, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Studies of Undergraduate and Graduate/Professional Student Debt at the University of Michigan [for May and August, 1985 Degree Recipients], 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - The University of Michigan Office of Financial Aid INAS Project Detail System Design Specification, 1989 (Box 1)